Partial Guide to the Memorial Library of Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- La colombe. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 390
  Opéra comique en deux actes de MM. J. Barbier et M. Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano. Réduite par Emile Perier. Paris, Choudens [1860] Pl. no. A. C. 738. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Presented for the first time at the Théâtre de Bade, August 3, 1860. Wotquenne, 2791.
- The daisy. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 391
  Song. The words translated from the French of Alex. Dumas, fils, by Henry Dulcken, Ph.D. The music composed by Ch. Gounod. London, Novello, Ewer [ca. 1871] Pl. no. 4581. First edition. Inscribed to Georgina Weldon by the composer.
- Faust. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 392
  Opéra en cinq actes, représenté pour la Ire fois à Paris, le 19 mars 1859. Paroles de MM. J. Barbier et M. Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition grand orchestre. Paris, Choudens [1859] P1. no. A. C. 675. The rare first edition of the full orchestral score. This is copy no. 14 issued to M. Cross. The ballet was published later and copies of the score containing it are later impressions. Wolffheim, II, 1412. This copy was presented to Sir Alexander Campbell Mackenzie by the family of Eaton Faning after the latter's death. Faning's signature appears inside the front cover. [Fragment of the manuscript of the bass solo, "La mot de Valentm' with orchestral accompamment (cf. separate entry) See item no. 397.]
- Faust. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 393
  Opéra en cinq actes de... Jules Barbier & Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition piano & chant arrangée par Leo Delibes... Paris, Choudens [1860] At head of title: 2e édition, avec les récitatifs, 2e édition, ajoutés par l'auteur. Ph. no. A. C. 664. Gounod's own copy with his signature. The score ends on p. 252.
- Faust. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 394
  Opéra en 5 actes de J. Barbier et M. Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano arrangée par Léo Delibes. Paris, Choudens [1861] At head of title: 3e édition avec récitatifs. Pl. nos. A. C. 364, 664. The score ends on p. 245.
- Faust. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 395
  Opera en 5 actes de J. Barbier et M. Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano arrangée par Léo Delibes. Paris, Choudens Père & Fils [1869] P1. no. A. C. 664. With 2 bars from Act III signed by the composer. A note at the head of the cast states that the piano arrangement is by Emile. Périer. This is the fourth edition with recitatives. The score ends on p. 267. On p. 265-267 is the score of "Apothéose.
- Faust. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 396
  Choeur des soldats.
- Faust. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 397
  La mort de Valentin. Fragment of the manuscript of bass solo with orchestral accompaniment. Inscribed to Raoul Madier de Montzan. 2 leaves (4 pages) 18 x 27 cm. In the first edition of the orchestral score.
- Jeanne d'Arc. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 398
  Drame en 5 actes et en vers de Jules Barbier. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano arrangée par Georges Bizet. Paris, E. Gérard et Cie. [1880] Ph. no. C. M. 11348. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Jesus de Nazareth. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 399
  Chant évangélique. Paroles de A. Porte. Musique de Charles Gounod... Paris, Lebeau, ainé [ca. 1876] Ph. nos. N. L. 50, A. G. 1365. First edition. Inscribed to Cte. da Nieuwskeka by the composer. Piano and vocal score. The first leaf following the score of the chant is a: "Choeur ad libitum ajouté par J. Consul," with the plate number A. G. 1365. The second leaf is a "Partie d'orgue ad libitum.
- Marche funèbre d'une marionette. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 400
  Musique de Ch. Gounod. Texte par Georges Price et Jean Ker Mary... Paris, Henry Lemoine [ca. 1883] Inscribed to the composer by both of the authors of the text.
- Vingt mélodies pour chant et piano par Ch. Gounod. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 401
  Paris, Choudens [ca. 1879] P1. no. 945. At head of title:1er recueil. First edition. inscribed to Mme. Camille Claude by the composer. "Edition pour mezzo-soprano ou baryton.
- Vingt melodies pour chant et piano par Ch. Gounod. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 402
  Paris, Choudens [ca. 1879] P1. no. A. C. 1803. At head of title: 2me recueil. First edition. "Edition pour mezzo-soprano ou baryton.
- Vingt mélodies pour chant et piano par Ch. Gounod. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 403
  Paris, Choudens [ca. 1879] P1. no. A. C. 2483. At head of title: 3me recueil. First edition. "Edition pour soprano ou tenor.
- Mireille. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 404
  Opéra en 5 actes, tiré du poëme de Frédéric Mistral par Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens [1864] P1. no. A. C. 1005. First edition, first issue. Mireille was first produced at the Théâtre Lyrique, Paris, on March 19, 1864, when it was in five acts, and a shortened version in three acts followed at the same theater on December 15 of the same year. The first and third editions cover these two productions and show tremendous differences. Midway between these there was a second edition, also showing considerable alterations. Wotquenne, 2793.
- Mireille. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 405
  Opéra en 5 actes, tiré du poëme de Frédéric Mistral par Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens [1864] P1. no. A. C. 1005. Second edition. Verso of p. 191 is number 192-200. Cf. note under entry for first edition, first issue.
- Mireille. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 406
  Opéra en 5 actes, tiré du poëme de Frédéric Mistral par Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens [1864] Pl. no. 1005. Second edition (variant). Cf. note under entry for first edition, first issue.
- Mireille. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 407
  Opéra en 5 actes, tiré du poëme de Frédéric Mistral par Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens [1864] P1. no. A. C. 1005. Third edition. Cf. note under entry for first edition, first issue.
- My beloved spake. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 408
  Song (with violoncello obligato). The words from The song of Solomon. The music by Ch. Gounod. London, Goddard [ca. 1873] P1. no. G. & Co. 159. First edition. Inscribed to Georgina Weldon by the composer.
- La nonne sanglante. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 409
  Opéra en cinq actes. Paroles de [MM.] E. Scribe et G. Delavigne. Musique de Charles Gounod. Representé pour Iére fois sur le Théâtre de l'Académie Imple. de Musique, le 18 8bre 1854. Partition piano et chant, arrangée par Georges Bizet... Paris, Imp. Jannot, 1854. Pl nos. 0-17 (A-D), 19-23. First edition. Bound with this is another version of the "Ballet-valse" with the same pl. no. 18A.
- Philémon et Baucis. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 410
  Opéra en deux actes de MM. Jules Barbier et Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano, réduite par Hector Salomon. Paris, Choudens [1860] Pl. nos. A. C. 704, 703, and 702. First edition. [2 copies; 1 copy inscribed to Albert Delacourtie] Presented for the first time at Paris, February 18, 1860. Wotquenne, 2790.
- Polyeucte. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 411
  Opéra en cinq actes. Paroles de Jules Barbier et Michel Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition, piano et chant réduite par H. Salomon. Paris, Henry Lemoine [ca. 1878] P1. no. 8139 H. First edition. Inscribed to Victor Warot by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, October 7, 1878. Wotquenne, 2797.
- La rédemption. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 412
  Triologie sacrée. Paroles et musique de Charles Gounod. Partition piano et chant arrangée par Berthold Tours... Londres, Novello, Ewer [1882] First edition. Inscribed to Albert Delacourtie by the composer. Wotquenne, 1134. [2 copies; 2nd copy inscribed to Warot]
- Autograph letter signed. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 412A
  To A1bert Delacourtie Paris, October 1, 1882.
- La reine de Saba. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 413
  Grand opéra en 5 actes de MM. Jules Barbier et Michel Carré. Mis en musique... par Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano arrangée par Georges Bizet. Paris, Choudens [1862] Pl. no. A. C. 880. First edition. Inscribed to Albert Delacourtie by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, February 28, 1862. Wotquenne, 2792.
- Requiem. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 414
  Dernière oeuvre de Ch. Gounod. Transcrit par Henri Büsser. A. Edition choeurs, soli S.C.T.B., accompagnement de piano... Paris, Choudens [ca. 1893] P1. no. A. C. 9791. First edition.
- Roméo et Juliette. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 415
  Opéra en 5 actes de J. Barbier et M. Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano, transcrite par Hector Salomon. Paris, Choudens Père & Fils [1873] Pl. no. A. C. 1411. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Louise Goudchaux by the composer. The inscription includes, three bars of music. Presented for the first time at Paris, April 27, 1867. Wotquenne, 2794.
- Roméo et Juliette. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 416
  Opéra en 5 actes de J. Barbier et M. Carré. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant & piano. Paris, Choudens [ca. 1873] P1. no. A. C. 1411. Third edition. Inscribed to Camille Bellaigue by the composer. With changes from score of first and second editions.
- Songs of France. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 417
  The words by celebrated French poets, and imitated in English by Henry F. Chorley. Composed by Charles Gounod. London, Cramer, Beale [ca. 1873] Pl. nos. 5369-5374. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Autograph letter signed. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 417A
  To "Le Rédacteur en Chief." [London] October 11, 1873. This long letter (4 pages) to the editor of a London newspaper relates to his treatment in England with regard to his rights to copyright protection. Gounod says that he could not even secure the rights to his opera Faust. He considers the law a farce which ruins the authors and protects the publishers.
- Stabat Mater. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 418
  Paraphrase en Français. Paroles de Mr. l'Abbé Castaing. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition grand orchestre. Paris, Choudens, [ca. 1871] P1. no. A. C. 1475. First edition. Inscribed to Georgina Weldon by the composer.
- Sweet baby sleep (Lullaby). / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 419
  The words by George Wither (1641) (from Sir Roundell Palmer's Book of praise). Composed by Ch. Gounod. London, Novello, Ewer. Pl. no. 4603. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Fétis, supp., I, p. 410.
- There is a green hill far away. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 420
  Sacred song written by Mrs. C. F. Alexander. The music by Ch. Gounod. London, Novello, Ewer [ca. 1871] Pl. no. 4577. Inscribed to G. Weldon by the composer. A song which has become one of the more familiar hymns in evangelical churches.
- Thy will be done. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 421
  A prayer in mezzo-soprano (with harmonium accompaniment ad libitum). The words by Charlotte Elliot. The music composed by Ch. Gounod. London, Goddard [ca. 1873) Pl. no. G. & Co. 119. First edition. Signed by the composer. The Italian text by G. Zaffira has been added in manuscript.
- Tobie (Tobias) Petit oratorio. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 422
  Paroles de H. Lefèvre. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens [1865] Pl. no. A. C. 1237. First edition. Inscribed to his wife Anna by the composer. Text in French and English. Wotquenne, 1133.
- La Toussaint. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 423
  Original manuscript 2 leaves (3 pages) 221/2 x 30 cm. Piano and vocal score. Inscribed to Mlle. Berthe de Besplas by the composer.
- Le tribut de Zamora. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 424
  Grand opéra en 4 actes de Ad. d'Ennery et Brésil. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Partition chant et piano transcrite par H. Salomon et L. Roques. Paris, Choudens [1881] Pl. no. A. C. 4633. First edition. Inserted is an autograph letter signed. To "Marie Anne." Paris, July 9, 1885.
- Ulysse. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 425
  Tragédie en cinq actes et en vers de Mr. Fr. Ponsard. Musique de Ch. Gounod. Accompag't de piano par A. de Garaudé. Paris, Choudens [1860] P1. no. B. C. 1299. First edition. Inscribed to Albert Delacourtie by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, June 18, 1852.
- Autograph letters signed. / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 426
  November 23, 1882-November 2, 1887. Paris [et al.] to Alfred Lyttleton of Novello & Co. An important group of thirty-eight letters to his publisher relating to many of his works. Accompanied by a translation of each letter by Dolores van Patten.
- Letter / GOUNOD, CHARLES FRANCOIS (1818-1893), MLM 426A
  Grainger, Percy. April 16, 1922 & Portait postcard.
- Passions-Cantate / GRAUN, CARL HEINRICH (1701-1759), MLM 427
  Der Tod Jesu, in einem Clavier-auszuge herausgegeben von Johann Adam Hiller...Breslau, Gottlieb Löwe, 1785. At head of title: Herrn Carl Heinrich Grauns. First edition. English text to some movements added in manuscript partly from Latrobe and partly from a manuscript in the University of Birmingham Library which gives the words used when this oratorio was performed at the Birmingham Musical Festival. Graun's Der Tod Jeru held to a considerable extent the same position in Germany that Handel's Messiah did in England. It was annually performed in Passion Week. Eitner, IV, p. 347. Wotquenne, 1136.
- [Sur les champs jaunes] Original manuscript signed. ca. 1900. 3 leaves (title-page, 4 pages) 251/2 x 381/2 cm. Piano and vocal score. Russian text. / GRETCHANINOFF, ALEXANDER (1864-), MLM 428
- / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 428A
  (ca. 1778)
- Le Huron. / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 429
  Comédie en deux actes et en vers, dédiée à son Excellence Mr. le Comte de Creutz. Mise en musique par André Grétry. Représentée pour la première fois par les Comédiens Italiens, le 20 aoust 1768. Paris, Béraux [ca. 1768] First edition. Orchestral score. The text is by Jean François Marmontel. Eitner, IV, 371; Wolffheim, II, 1427; Wotquenne, 1611.
- Autograph letter signed / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 429A
  To "Citoyen Ministre," Paris, "3 Pluviôse An. XI," in which Grétry acknowledges and thanks him for the grant of a pension. [Also included are two portrait postcards.]
- Richard Coeur de Lion. / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 430
  Comédie en 3 actes en prose et en vers par M. Sedaine. Représentée, pour la première fois, à Paris par les Comédiens Italiens Ordinaires du Roi, le 2 octobre 1784; et à Fontainebleau, devant leurs Majestés, le 25 octobre 1785. Dédiée à Madame Des Entelles. Mise en musique par M. Grétry. Oeuvre XXIV. Paris, Houbaut [ca. 1785] First edition. Orchestral score. The German text has been added in contemporary manuscript. Grétry's most famous opera. Hirsch, II, 353; Wotquenne, 1642.
- Autograph letter signed. / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 430A
  To M. de Croix, Secrétaire du Roy, à Lille, Paris, April 4, 1789. This refers to the success of his Barbe bleu and Aspasie.
- Zémire et Azor. / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 431
  Comédie-ballet en vers et en quatre actes. Représentée devant sa Majesté à Fontainebleau le 9 novembre 1771, et à la Comédie Italienne le 16 décembre 1771, par M. Grétry. Paris, Houbaut [1772] At head of title: Oeuvre VIIe. First edition. Orchestral score. The text is by Jean François Marmontel. Wolffheim, II, 1434; Wotquenne, 1620.
- Quarante-trois lettres / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 431A
  inédites de Grétry à Alexandre Rousselin, 1806-1812.
- Autograph note signed. / GRETRY, ANDRE ERNEST MODESTE (1741-1813), MLM 431B
  To an unidentified correspondent, Paris, December 2, 1809.
- Zwei elegische Melodien nach Gedichten v. A. O. Vinje für Streichorchester componirt von Edvard Grieg. / GRIEG, EDVARD HAGERUP (l843-19O7), MLM 432
  Op. 34. Klavierauszug zu 2 Händen von Componisten. Original manuscript signed. March 9, 1887. 4 leaves (title-page, 6 pages) 26 x 34 cm.
- Zwei Melodien für Streichorchester (nach eigenen Liedern) von Edvard Grieg. / GRIEG, EDVARD HAGERUP (l843-19O7), MLM 433
  Opus 53 Leipzig, C. F. Peters [ca. 1875] Pl. no. 7628. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. The contents include "Norsk" and "Det förste möde.
- Zweite Orchestersuite aus der Musik zu "Peer Gynt" (Dramatische Dichtung von H. Ibsen) zur Concertaufführung neu bearbeitet von Edvard Grieg. Op. 55. / GRIEG, EDVARD HAGERUP (l843-19O7), MLM 434
  Partitur. Leipzig, C. F. Peters [1876] Pl. no. 7672. First edition.
- Signed photograph. / GRIEG, EDVARD HAGERUP (l843-19O7), MLM 434A
  Cologne, November, 1878.
- Grand Canyon suite. / GROFE, FERDE (1892-), MLM 435
  Robbins miniature orchestra score. New York, Robbins Music Corporation, c1943. First edition. Inscribed for the collection by the composer.
- Black Gold-Symphonic Poem. / GROFE, FERDE (1892-), MLM 435A
- La chambre blanche. / GROVLEZ, GABRIEL (1879-1944), MLM 436
  Dix mélodies sur les poèmes de Henry Bataille. 1. Berceuse; 2. Berceuse; 3. Chanson; 4, Songe; 5, Les villages; 6. La maison; 7. Les yeux; 8. Promenade; 9. La vie; 10. L'adieu. Musique de Gabriel Grovlez. Paris, Alphonse Leduc [1906] Pl. no. A. L. 11,327. First edition. Inscribed to Madame Edwards by the composer.
- Maïmouna. Fantaisie-ballet en 2 tableaux de P. André Gérard. / GROVLEZ, GABRIEL (1879-1944), MLM 437
  Musique de Gabriel Grovlez. Paris, Société d'Editions "Théâtre-Musique," c1921. Pl. no. S.E.T.M. 7. First edition. Inscribed to "Mary" by the composer.
- The favorite songs in the comic opera Le pazzie d'Orlando by Sigr. Guglielmi. / GUGLIELMI, PIETRO (1727-1804), MLM 438
  London, R. Bremer [ca. 1771] First edition. This contains only "Orlando," p. 40-57. Orchestral score.
- [VI Missae] / HABERMANN, FRANZ JOHANN (1706-1785), MLM 439
  At foot of recto of first leaf of each signature: Messe del Signore Habermann. Without title-page, caption-title, place, or date [ca. 1750] Fétis, IV, p. 173-174. [Shelved with item no. 833.]
- Agnus Dei à deux voix (soprano et baryton) [par] Reynaldo Hahn. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 440
  Paris, Heugel, c1897. Pl. no. 18745. First edition. Inscribed by the Composer.
- Au clair de lune. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 441
  Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Texte et dessins de Louis Montégut. Avec une preface de Alphonse Daudet. Paris, Quantin [1892] First edition. Inscribed to Charles Gounod by the composer.
- Cantique sur le bonheur des justes et sur le malheur des réprouves. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 442
  Paroles de Jean Racine. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, 1896. P1. no. H. et Cie. 18,386. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Suzette Lemaire by the composer.
- La chère blessure. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 443
  Poésie de Mme. Blanchecotte. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, c1900. Pl. no. H. & Cie. 20364. Caption title. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Les cygnes. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 444
  Poésie de Armand Renaud. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, 1894. Pl. no. H. et Cie. 8047. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Suzette [Lemaire] by the composer. The inscription includes three bars from the score.
- Dans l'été. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 445
  Poésie de Marceline Desbordes-Valmore. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, c1908. Pl. no. H. & Cie. 23,906. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- D'une prison. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 446
  Poésie de Paul Verlaine. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, c1894. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Les fontaines. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 447
  Poésie de Henri Régnier. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel [c1910] P1. no. H. & Cie. 24,794. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Suzanne Lemaire by the composer.
- L'île du rêve. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 448
  Idylle polynésienne de Pierre Loti. André Alexandre & Georges Hartmann. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, c1897. Pl. no. H. et Cie. 18767. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. Adèle Meyer by the composer.
- Le marchand de Venise. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 449
  Opéra en 3 actes et 5 tableaux d'après la comédie de Shakespeare. Adaptation en vers de Miguel Zamocois. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. La partition chant et piano. Paris, Heugel [c1935] Pl. no. H. 30898. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Thomas by the composer with a separate inscription also to Mlle. Thomas by the librettist.
- [Les muses pleurant la mort de Ruskin] / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 450
  Original manuscript signed. On front cover in the Composer's handwriting: "A Marcel Proust. Les muses pleurant la mort de Ruskin. R. H. 1902." 10 leaves (17 pages, music) 281/4 x 33 cm. Inscribed to Mlle. Lemaire by the composer.
- Nausicaa. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 451
  Opéra en deux actes. Poème de René Fauchois. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Partition piano et chant. Paris, Heugel [c1919] Pl. no. H. & Cie. 26550. First edition. Inscribed to Emile Archaimbaud by the composer.
- La paix. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 452
  Rondel. Poésie de Theodore de Banville. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, c1898. P1. no. H. et Cie. 19021. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Phidyle. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 453
  Original manuscript signed "R. H." 2 leaves (2 pages) 27 x 351/2 cm. Voice part.
- [Portraits de peintres] / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 454
  Original manuscript [ca. 1896] consisting of four parts: Albert Cuyp. 4 leaves (4 pages) Signed "R. H." at end. In folder with title in the composer's handwriting. Paulus Potter. 2 leaves (2 pages) Signed "R. H." at end. In folder with title on front and back in the composer's handwriting. Anton van Dyck. 3 leaves (3 pages) Signed "R. H." at end. In folder with title and inscription signed by the composer. Antoine Watteau. 4 leaves (4 pages) Signed by the composer at the end. In folder with title in the composer's handwriting. The four manuscripts are laid in a folder upon the front-cover of which the composer has written: "A Madame Madeleine Lemaire. Portraits de peintres, d'après la Marcel Proust. Manuscrits originaux pour être reproduits dans le livre de M. P. Reynaldo Hahn." With these manuscripts are the corresponding engraved scores.
- Le ruban dénoué. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 455
  Suite de valses. Souvenirs d'Albi et d'ailleurs. Nos. 1-8, 10-12. Original manuscript. 79 leaves (8 title-pages, signed, 138 pages music) 27 x 361/2 cm. Score for two pianos. There is a long explanatory note in the composer's handwriting at the bottom of p. [2.-3.] of No.12, signed "R.H.
- [Sonatine en ut majeur] / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 456
  Paris, Heugel [1907] P1. no. H. & Cie. 23,327. First corrected proof sheets without Caption. On p. I: "A. M. Louis Diémer, Sonatine en ut majeur, Reynaldo Hahn," opposite p.19: at end of score, "(1907)," and on verso of p. 19: "Une autre épreuve S. V. P., Reynaldo Hahn," with corrections throughout, all in the composer's handwriting.
- Le souvenir d'avoir chanté. Poésie de Catulle Mendès. Musique de Reynaldo Hahn. Paris, Heugel, c1898. Pl. no. H. et Cie. 19152. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. / HAHN, REYNALDO (1875-), MLM 457
- [Allegro a capriccio] / HALEVY, JACQUES FRANCOIS FROMENTAL ELIAS (1799-1862), MLM 458